Joshua Everett Manchester, UK

Website: joshuaeverett.co.uk - Email: joshuaeverett95@gmail.com - Mobile: +44 (0)7758 664365

Software engineer with 10 years development experience specialising in Android. I approach everything with a high attention to detail and creativity, and I am passionate about including accessibility and usability throughout my work.

Employment

Senior Design System Engineer - Deliveroo, Remote, UK 2022 - Present

Senior Android developer in the team owning Deliveroo's design system. Responsible for the implementation and maintenance of the design system components and foundations across all four Android apps. Collaboration with the designer and other engineers in the team, alongside the wider Android community to deliver the design systems requirements as effectively as possible.

Work delivered:

- Android library for design tokens, built with Style Dictionary for views and Jetpack Compose.
- Improved tooling for design system, adding theme configuration to component browser app.
- Introduce themed icon to the Deliveroo app, utilising modern Android OS features.

Senior Software Engineer - BBC iPlayer, Manchester, UK 2021 - 2022

Senior developer on the BBC iPlayer Android app, which served 7 million viewers. Responsible for the video player, building new features in Kotlin. Lead app releases in Google Play and Amazon consoles. Mentoring new developers joining the team, as well as junior developers across the BBC.

Work delivered:

- Development of heavily requested autoplay to next episode, utilising a feature toggle.
- Improved monitoring for issue diagnosis, collaborating with the media player team.
- Enabling Jetpack Compose to be used in the app, setting up theming and a sample app.

Software Engineer - BBC Sport, Manchester, UK 2019 - 2021

Developed the BBC Sport app, which served 2 million fans. Heavily involved in collaboration with the News team to develop a shared component library, providing reusable UI to both apps. Set up a cross department working group for accessibility, improving processes and visibility of issues.

Work delivered:

- New version of article pages built with shared component library, loading ~6x faster.
- Creation of a new onboarding experience, prioritising accessibility and screen reader users.
- Running multivariate experiments with users, informing the approach to mandatory sign-in.

Graduate Software Engineer - BBC, London/Manchester, UK 2017 - 2019

Completed 6-month rotations for iPlayer TV, journalism tools and Sport Android app teams. Gained a wide range of experience by working with different teams/types of agile development. Volunteered at STEM sessions running coding challenges with school children, as well as at BBC events.

Web Developer - Intergral GmbH, Stuttgart, Germany 2015 - 2016

Worked within the web team developing a cloud service for the core product, FusionReactor. Gaining experience on web frameworks, understanding and delivering requirements into the product. Mentored and paired with other developers, running onboarding for the next placement.

Skills

Android Development

Building Android apps using Kotlin and Java in Android Studio. Strong knowledge in concepts such as layouts, theming, coroutines and architecture patterns (MVVM, MVC). Experience using testing frameworks (JUnit, Espresso). Usage of modern Android tools such as Jetpack libraries including Jetpack Compose. Building and publishing Android libraries.

{} Software Development

Working within an agile team, collaborating with other developers through pairing on tasks and code reviews. Adhering to good software engineering principles, ensuring I write easy to understand and maintainable code. Extensive experience using Git with Github.

Accessibility

Extensive knowledge in making Android apps accessible following WCAG/BBC guidelines, using TalkBack and testing with Android's Accessibility Suite. Recognition of different disabilities, the additional needs associated, and the assistive technology required.

A Design Systems/User Experience

Contributions to a design system, providing technical considerations. Ran research sessions with users gaining insight into how they use app functionality. Working alongside UX to develop accessible designs/interactions. Proficient with Material Design concepts.

Cloud Development

Experience with AWS, using services like CloudWatch to gather and query monitoring events. Use of CI tools such as Github Actions, Bitrise, CircleCI and Jenkins to ensure continuous delivery. Running Android emulator and device tests on Firebase, utilising Fladle.

</> Web Development

Develop and host multiple modern web applications built from scratch, using libraries such as React and Angular. Build services on AWS with TypeScript. Strong knowledge with CSS. Usage of hybrid mobile frameworks such as ionic/react native.

Education

Loughborough University - Web Development

2013 - 2017

Graduated with First class BSc (hons) with a year working in industry. Awarded two team project prizes during my degree for achieving the highest mark in each coursework deliverable.

Interests

Music - Passion for live music and collecting vinyl records, as well as playing guitar and bass. Sport - I love playing football, keeping active, and following Formula 1, football, cricket and the NFL. Creativity - I've recently got into photography and love creative projects like drawing and painting.

References can be provided upon request. For more information on me and my work/projects please visit my website.